(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T09:16:16.116467",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
迷いの森にある 本当
Within a forest of delusion, truly...
探しに行く 月のヒカリ
I go to search for the moonlight.
羊歯を踏んで 足を濡らして
Stepping over ferns, wetting my feet,
ひたぶる ほゝり 夏の小道
Along a quiet, murmuring summer path.
よく 笑って 泣いて 見つめ 合って
Laughing, crying, and gazing at each other,
おそるおそる 恋に 堕ちた
Cautiously, we fell in love.
ふたり歩き出した 違う 方 へ
Walking down different paths,
呼び合う 声 だけ もどかしく
Only the sound of our calling voices frustrates us.
find me in the wonderland
そろそろ 手を 汚して
Before long, getting my hands dirty,
自分の欲しい ものを
Chasing after what I desire,
追いかけてみる
and giving chase...
三つ編みをほどいて
Untying my braided hair,
同じ 星を 齧る
We bite into the same star,
ふたりに なる 寂しさが
becoming a pair, as loneliness
まだ明るい 夢の おどり
arrives at the bright shore of dreams...
食べかけで残した 心だって
Leaving my heart half-eaten behind,
ここから始まる 歌になる
A song begins from right here.
世界は君のものさ
The world is yours...
どこへ行こうか
Where should we step next?
あなたは笑う
You're smiling.
踏み出してみようか
Let's try looking around.
後ろめたさが
The starry sky behind...
私を誘う
is inviting me.
Funny, it's Wonderland.
Welcome to Wonderland.
どうしたって生まれ変わる
No matter what you do, you are reborn.
ことの強い意志が
The strong will...
いつよがわしんちょうな
It was always...
命だった私だけじゃ道は
Just my life.
いつからがい星を数え繋がり合わせ
また知らない夏の星座
見つめあって泣いて優しさになって
ここから始まる物語は一人じゃないのよ夢のようでしょう私を歌う
寂しさは耐えられない
頭のもとへと二人集おう
何もおもいどおりにならないことが始まったから
踏み出してみようか
目隠しのように手の鳴る方へ
In your wonderland...
あなたが迷う場所に
明かりを灯し続け
あなたが一歩退いて
霊々しく笑いましょう
どうひとりじゃないのよとても怖いれしあわせなんて
寂しさは耐えられない
頭のもとへと二人集おう
手形があってあなたがいって踏み出してみようか
愛する人が私を誘う
Funny, it's Wonderland.
綺麗になった息切れになって
あなたの歌を歌って
delete
優しい言葉をなくした闇の中
最後の祈りも静かに消えていったよ気はとぶ君は一人出口のない夢の中で涙だけが道を描いた誰にも届かず朽ちていく歌がある
優しい言葉を失くした闇の中
In the darkness that lost its kind words,
最後の祈りも静かに消え去った
even the last prayer quietly faded away.
夜明けは遠く君は一人
The dawn is far and you're alone,
出口の無い夢の中で
inside a dream with no exit,
涙だけが道を照らした
only the tears were shining on the way.
誰にも届き朽ちて行く歌がある
There is a song that decays without reaching anyone,
悲しみ一つも奏でられずに終わる
it finishes without even playing a single sadness.
声もなく君はただ泣いた
You just cried without even a voice.
ノイズが途切れて
The noise got interrupted
誰かが数を数えた
as someone counted the amount.
光をもたらす
The person of fate
定めの人は来ない
that would bring light isn't coming,
どよんだ時間は斑に凍り付いて
as the stagnated time is frozen into spots.
恐れを研いだ刃を手にして
With the blade with which we sharpened fear in our hands,
抱きしめる形をして
taking the shape of hugging each other,
君と僕は傷を重ねた
you and I piled up wounds.
何処にも届かず君の声は潰れた
Your voice was wasted without reaching anywhere,
消え行くことさえ
even the disappearing things
誰も気付かぬままに
remained unnoticed by everyone,
無造作に数字を増やした
casually increasing the numbers.
いつか光の中で
Someday in the light
側にいてくれると信じた
I believed you'd be by my side.
形のないぼくたちは
We, who have no shape,
形のある世界へと
looked for the way to eventually return
いつか帰る道を探した
to the world that has a shape.
忘れてしまった
Looking for the voice of
優しい人の声を
the kind person I had completely forgotten,
探して彷徨う道は何処まで遠い
I am wandering, the road seems endless.
声もなく君はただ泣いた
You just cried without even a voice,
道はヤガテ途絶えた
the road eventually stopped.
形のない僕たちは
We, who have no shape,
形のある場所へと
to a place with shape,
いつか帰る道を探した
searched for the way to eventually return.
忘れてしまった
We forgot
優しい人の声を
the voice of a kind person.
探して彷徨う
Searching and wandering,
道はどこまで遠い
how far is the road?
優しさを知る
Knowing only kindness,
人の声を
the voice of a person...
探して彷徨う
searching and wandering,
道はどこまで遠い
how far is the road?
声もなく
With no voice,
日々はただ流れた
the days simply flowed by.
道はやがてほどけて
The road eventually unraveled,
声もなく
with no voice,
日々はただ流れた
the days simply flowed by.
道はやがてほどけて
The road eventually unraveled.
わあ！
Wah!
おはよう、こんにちは、こんばんは！
Good morning, afternoon, evening!
Welcome to my birthday live!
Yay, it's finally happening!
Thank you guys for being so patient.
I know this was originally planned for around May, around my birthday,
but it's finally happening in December!
Thank you so much, everyone, for being patient and supporting me so this could happen.
Thank you so, so much staff-san for all your hard work!
I'm so happy, and I'm so nervous, can you tell?
So, did you guys enjoy the first two songs, Wonderland and delete?
Wonderland is an MS song, it's not Ina's live without an MS song.
I don't think it's as well known, but it's definitely one of my favorite songs by her, so I wanted to perform it for you guys someday.
And delete, it's actually an insert song in the Sword Art Online movie, Ordinal Scale,
and I really like the song in the movie, and I, you know, I wanted to perform it for you guys.
mythical mythical songs
Yeah!
And as you can see, we're kind of in a monochrome world.
You'll be like, "Hey, did did they forget to add in the colors to this this place? Like, what's happening?" But, you know,
You'll be like, "Hey, did they forget to add colors to this place? What's happening?" But, you know,
I've always said before that before I joined hololive and all, the world kind of looked bland and monochrome,
I've always said that before I joined hololive, the world kind of looked bland and monochrome,
but as time went on here where I met all wonderful members, wonderful staff, and it became a lot more colorful,
but as time went on here, where I met wonderful members and staff, it became a lot more colorful.
so I wanted to kind of add that into the special live,
So I wanted to incorporate that into this special live,
my first birthday live!
So, yeah, maybe, you know, if we go down this live, we'll find some color again.
So, yeah, maybe as we go through this live, we'll find some color again.
And of course, I got to mention the title of the live, Neverland Paradox.
And of course, I have to mention the title of the live: Neverland Paradox.
It sounds very difficult, but if you break it down, Neverland is kind of this imaginary, ideal world that's not supposed to exist.
It sounds very complex, but if you break it down, Neverland is an imaginary, ideal world that shouldn't exist.
But if it doesn't exist, what do we know about it? Why? How? It's a paradox.
But if it doesn't exist, how do we know about it? Why? How? It's a paradox.
So, you know, kind of like that. Let's pretend that this world here right here is Neverland and we'll go down this journey together, yeah, together!
So, you know, let's pretend that this world right here is Neverland, and we'll go on this journey together—yeah, together!
Anyways, if you want to talk about this live somewhere, let me see the comments later too. Hashtag #INAInaNeverland
Anyway, if you want to talk about this live online, let me see your comments later too. Hashtag #INAInaNeverland
Hashtag #INAInaNeverland is it here? Is it here? Is it here? Is it here? Somewhere?
Hashtag #INAInaNeverland—is it here? Is it here? Is it here? Somewhere?
So tweet about it, tell your friends it's happening! Ina's first birthday live, yay!
Anyways, I hope you'll have a lot of fun during the live. Let's enjoy our trip through Neverland together!
Anyway, I hope you have a lot of fun during the live. Let's enjoy our trip through Neverland together!
Never-Everland! Never-ever-Neverland! Yeah, let's go!
ダミーダミー
Dummy Dummy
一人じゃ出来ないことを探してみたよ
I searched for things I couldn't do by myself,
二人じゃなくちゃ出来ない何かを
for something I'd need someone else to do.
でもその答えを捜せば捜すほど
Yet the longer I search for that answer,
誰かと笑ってる僕を殺したくなる
the more I want to kill the self that smiles with others.
「1＋1が一番美しいよ」
"1 + 1 is the most beautiful."
僕はそう思えなくて
I couldn't see it that way;
誰かに縛られてると思いたくて
I wanted to believe I was bound by someone,
そんな自分が一番美しいと思った
and thought that kind of self was the most beautiful.
二人で作れないことがたくさんある
There are so many things that can't be made with two,
一人で作れることが多すぎて
and so many things I can do alone,
だから僕がもっと大量に必要だよ
so I need to mass-produce myself even more.
そして誰かに僕の役を押し付けた
And so I forced my role onto someone else.
僕の声は一言も葉にならない、なれない
My voice cannot—no, will never—form a single word,
だからここで誰かが演じる僕を見てるよ
so right here, I watch someone else play my role.
僕はそう思いたくて
That's how I wanted to think,
誰かが演じる僕が僕のそれより美しくて輝いているから
because the me played by someone else shines brighter and more beautifully than mine.
僕に良く似たアナタに僕をプレゼントするよ
I'll present myself to you, who look so much like me.
いらなくなったらそっとティッシュにくるんで捨てて
If you don't need it, wrap it gently in a tissue and throw it away.
代わりに僕が君を演じるよ
In exchange, I'll play your role.
いらなくなったらゴムにくるんで捨てて
If you don't need it, wrap it up and throw it away.
代わりに僕が君を演じるよ
In exchange, I'll play your role.
なくなったらそっと一緒にくるんで捨てて
And when it's gone, let's wrap it up together and throw it away.
いらなくなったらここにくるんだ捨てるよ
When you don't need it anymore, come here and throw it away.
どうして みんなが 幸せなの？
Just why is everyone so happy?
この世界の こと 聞きたいって、知りたいって
Wanting to know and learn about this world,
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を澄ませて
Everyone is listening intently in the park by the waterside,
わくわくするね ねぇ、オンディーヌ？
So excited, right, Ondine?
ハイハイイ！
Right, right!
さあさあ、みなさん 教えてあげまーす！
Now then, everyone, I'll enlighten you!
みんなが気になりすぎて困っていること
About the things on your mind that bother you so much,
疑問に思いすぎて食事も喉を通らないこと
Or questions that leave you unable to even swallow your food,
ぜーんぶ丸ごと 教えてあげまーす！
I will tell you everything, all of it!
えー、みなさんが 幸福なのは…義務なんです。
Uh, everyone's happiness... is a duty.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
果たしていますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
我々、幸福安心委員会っていう名の素晴らしい団体は、
We, the wonderful organization called the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee,
みなさまの幸福を願い そして、支えまーす！
Wish for your happiness and support you!
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
ですから、安心して 義務を果たすように！
So please rest assured and fulfill your duty!
みなさまの幸福が 我々の幸せ。
Your happiness is our happiness.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
ですから、安心して 義務を果たすように！
So please rest assured and fulfill your duty!
みなさまの幸福が 我々の幸せ。
Your happiness is our happiness.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？ 果たしていますか？
Are you happy? It's your duty, right? Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら……
If you are not happy...
絞首 斬首 銃殺 釜茹で 溺死 電気 火あぶり 生き埋め 薬殺 石打ち 鋸 はりつけ
Hanging, beheading, firing squad, boiling, drowning, electrocution, burning, live burial, poison, stoning, sawing, crucifixion
好きなのを 選んでね♪
Just pick the one you like♪
ハイハイイ！
Right, right!
さあさあ、みなさん 幸福だけが満ちてまーす！
Now then, everyone, happiness is overflowing everywhere!
不安とか不満、 なにひとつ ないんでしょう？
You don't have a single worry or dissatisfaction, do you?
コワイ、コワイわ！ 幸福すぎて、恐いわ。
I'm scared, so scared! This happiness is too terrifying.
ホントに みんなが幸福なのは？
Is everyone truly happy?
この世界の 外 行きたいって、逃げたいって
Wanting to go to the outside world, wanting to escape,
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を塞いで
Everyone was covering their ears by the waterside,
びくびくしてた ねぇ、ウンディニー？
Looking so frightened, right, Undine?
ハイハイイ！
Right, right!
さあさあ、みなさん 死にましたー！
Now then, everyone, he is dead!
オンディーヌをふった騎士は 死にましたー！
The knight who turned down Ondine is now dead!
葬儀に出るなら、向こうに並べ！
If you're going to the funeral, line up over there!
それ以外は 幸福に暮らせ！ 以上。
Otherwise, live happily! That is all.
ほんとに みんなが 幸せなの？
Is everyone truly happy?
この世界の 外へ 行きたいて 逃げたいて
Wanting to go outside this world, wanting to escape,
水辺の公園で みんなが耳を 塞いで
Everyone was covering their ears by the waterside,
びくびくしてた ねぇ、オンディーヌ？
Looking so frightened, right, Ondine?
ハイハイイ！
Right, right!
さあさあ、みなさん 死にましたー！
Now then, everyone, he is dead!
オンディーヌをふった騎士は 死にましたー！
The knight who turned down Ondine is now dead!
葬儀に出るなら、向こうに並べ！
If you're going to the funeral, line up over there!
それ以外は 幸福に暮らせ！ 以上。
Otherwise, live happily! That is all.
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
義務なんです、義務ですよ？
It's your duty, it's your duty, okay?
義務なんです、
It's your duty,
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
義務なんです、義務ですよ？
It's your duty, it's your duty, okay?
義務なんです、
It's your duty,
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, okay?
義務なんです
It's your duty.
義務ですよ？
It's your duty, okay?
義務なんです
It's your duty.
幸福なのは義務なんです
It is your duty to be happy.
義務なんです
It's your duty.
義務ですよ？
It's your duty, okay?
義務なんです
It's your duty.
幸せじゃないなら……
If you are not happy...
死ね
Then die!
童話は さっき死んだみたい
The fairytale seems to have died moments ago
煉瓦の病棟で うまく歌えなくて
in the brick hospital ward, I can't sing right at all
霧に煙る夜 浮かべる赤い月
On the night shrouded in fog, a red moon floats
ほら見てよ 私を 目を逸らさないで
Hey, look at me, don't avert your eyes
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
Behind the black cell bars, I was born
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Go wish for the price of malice, exactly as you desire
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now I'll grant you justice, destroy it before you're destroyed
因果の代償を払い 共に行こう
I'll pay the price of karma and go together with you,
名前のない怪物
monster without a name
耳鳴りがしてさ 鉄筋網うざっくって
My ears are ringing, the barbed wire is rattling so noisily
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
that I can't recall the melody from that day
雨はまだ止まない 何にも見えないの
The rain hasn't stopped yet, I can't see anything
ほら見てよ こんなに大きくなったの
Hey, look at how big I've grown
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Make the black rain fall from this sky, because I'm undesired
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
I cracked into a nervous breakdown to my lovely onlookers who are just as guilty
さあ今振るえ正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now, exercise that justice, embracing a wound that can't be wiped away
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう
I'll accept this body and go together with you,
名前のない怪物
monster without a name
ああ 神の告げる 真ノ世界ヲ
Ah, God tells of the true world
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
Behind the black cell bars, I was born
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Go wish for the price of malice, exactly as you desire
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now I'll grant you justice, destroy it before you're destroyed
因果の代償を払い 報いよ 名もなき怪物
I'll pay the price of karma, take retribution, nameless monster
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Make the black rain fall from this sky, because I'm undesired
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
I cracked into a nervous breakdown to my lovely onlookers who are just as guilty
さあ今震える正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now, exercise that justice, embracing a wound that can't be wiped away
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう
I'll accept this body and go together with you,
名前のない怪物
monster without a name
ああ 神の告げる 真ノ世界ヲ
Ah, God tells of the true world
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
Behind the black cell bars, I was born
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Go wish for the price of malice, exactly as you desire
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now I'll grant you justice, destroy it before you're destroyed
因果の代償を払い 共に行こう
I'll pay the price of karma and go together with you,
名前のない怪物
monster without a name
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Make the black rain fall from this sky, because I'm undesired
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
I cracked into a nervous breakdown to my lovely onlookers who are just as guilty
さあ今振るえ正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now, exercise that justice, embracing a wound that can't be wiped away
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう
I'll accept this body and go together with you,
名前のない怪物
monster without a name
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Make the black rain fall from this sky, because I'm undesired
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛する同罪の傍観者達に
I cracked into a nervous breakdown to my lovely onlookers who are just as guilty
さあ今振るえ正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて
Now, exercise that justice, embracing a wound that can't be wiped away
この身体を受け入れ 共に行こう
I'll accept this body and go together with you,
名前のない怪物
monster without a name
悲しみは笑いましょう
Let sadness laugh away
生きってマリオネット
Life is just a marionette
心臓がスイングしたら
If your heart starts to swing
琴は如何？
How about a piano?
1・2・2・1・2・2・1・2・2・3
One, two, two, one, two, two, one, two, two, three
私上手く踊れないわ
I can't dance well enough
痛みも　恨みも　悲しみも
Pain, hatred, and sorrow
混ぜて　こねて
Mix them, knead them,
おやすみのキス
And a goodnight kiss
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？　踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望　欲望　this is the life!
Despair, desire, this is the life!
Shadow life!
余計なこと考えないで
Without thinking about unnecessary things
ひとつになりましょう
Let's become one
いいな　いいな
How nice, how nice,
人間って　人間って　いいな
Being human is so nice!
ランランラン　ランララ　ラン
Lan lan lan, lan lara lan
泣きたいのに笑えちゃう
Even though I want to cry, I end up laughing
人生ってピエロ
Life is just a pierrot
本当の心隠して
Hiding my true feelings
笑うフリをするの
And putting on a smile
1・2・2・1・2・2・1・2・2・3
One, two, two, one, two, two, one, two, two, three
私うまく生きれないわ
I can't live gracefully enough
本音も　ウソも　不安も
Truths, lies, and anxiety
溶かして　蓋して
Melting them, covering them up
おやすみなさい
Good night to you
シャル・ウィ・ドリーム？　夢見ましょう
Shall we dream? Let's dream
寝ても覚めても　this is the life!
Sleeping or waking, this is the life!
Shadow life!
目を閉じて
Close your eyes,
嫌なこと　ぜんぶぜんぶ忘れましょう
Forget all of those bad things
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？　不器用でも
Shall we dance? Even if clumsy,
あがいて　もがいて　this is the life!
Struggling and striving, this is the life!
Shadow step?
余計なこと考えないで
Don't think about unnecessary things
ステップを踏み鳴らせ！
Stamp your feet to the beat!
シャル・ウィ・スマイル？
Shall we smile?
今だけは
For just now,
一緒に笑ってみませんか
Won't you smile along with me?
Shadow dance!
今だけはぜんぶ忘れて
For just now, forget it all
一緒に飛びましょう
Let's jump together!
シャル・ウィ・スマイル？　今だけは
Shall we smile? For just now,
一緒には笑ってみませんか
Won't you laugh together with me?
Shadow dance!
今だけはぜんぶ忘れて
For just now, forget it all
一緒に飛びましょう
Let's jump together!
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？　踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望　欲望　this is the life!
Despair, desire, this is the life!
Shadow life!
余計なこと考えないで
Without thinking about unnecessary things
ひとつになりましょう
Let's become one
いいな　いいな
How nice, how nice,
人間って　いいな
Being human, so nice!
いいな　いいな
How nice, how nice,
人間って　人間って　いいな
Being human, being human, so nice!
ランランラン　ランララ　ラン
Lan lan lan, lan lara lan
花が寝る夜
The night when flowers sleep,
波に映った星
stars reflected on the waves,
うねる月が
the undulating moon
足をくすぐる
tickles my feet.
流れる光に
If I follow the flowing light
沿って行ってみたら
and go along it,
耳に囁いた
I wonder if it will reach you
君に届くかな
who whispered in my ear.
今手を繋いでも
Even if we hold hands now,
精一杯抱きしめてみても
even if I embrace you with all my might,
空は秋に満ちるんだ
the sky is filled with autumn.
指先でゆらゆらと
With my fingertips, swaying,
その動きが
that movement
止まった時計の針に踏み込んだ
stepped onto the hands of a stopped clock.
固まった願いさえ離れた今は
Now that even our solidified wishes have drifted apart,
その笑顔を
I know
知っているよ
that smile.
光歌う夜目に映った空
The sky reflected in the night eyes singing of light,
さわやかな香りがくすぐる
a refreshing scent tickles.
足跡を合わせて歩いてみたら
If I walked matching my footsteps,
私を見ていた君に届くかな
I wonder if it will reach you who was watching me.
ずっと手を繋いでも
Even if we hold hands forever,
君について行ってみても
even if I try following you,
空は雨に染まるんだ
the sky is stained with rain.
君を呼び出した声の形が
The shape of the voice that called out to you
乾いた色を濡らして
moistened the dry colors.
強く叫んだ声が散らばった今は
Now that the voice I shouted strongly has scattered,
その言葉を
I know
知っているよ
those words.
君は分かっているかな
I wonder if you understand,
教えてくれた
you taught me
戻らないその幸せは
that happiness that won't return.
花が寝る夜波に映った星
Stars reflected on the waves on a night when flowers sleep,
光った月が消えていく
the shining moon fades away.
指先でゆらゆらとその動きが
With my fingertips, swaying, that movement
止まった時計の針に踏み込んだ
stepped onto the hands of a stopped clock.
雲が描いた列車そよぐ髪
A train drawn by clouds, hair fluttering in the breeze—
その笑顔を
I know
知っているよ
that smile.
Hi, welcome back!
That was still quite a lot of songs.
And look, we got some color back! What color is this? Uh, Violet?
Well, I hope you guys enjoyed the songs. We sang a couple of songs. Uh, first one being, uh, Dummy Dummy by Deco*27.
Ina-san.
Um, it's a song I've been fond of for quite a long time, actually.
It's uh I think it's lesser known than some of his really, you know, famous songs, but
it's it has a special place in my heart.
So I really wanted to sing it for you guys, and I hope you guys enjoy it.
Yeah, the song I sang after that is called "Kocchi Koufuku Anshin Iinkai Desu."
I think it's a really fun song that's perfect for cult...
Although I wouldn't know anything about being a cult.
Definitely not a cult, by the way.
[Laughter]
Yeah, and uh the song after that was "Namei no Nai Kaibutsu."
Um, if you guys know, I really love EGOIST, and one of my favorite songs by them is actually this song.
Uh and I sang it, I think, once or twice in karaoke before.
But I really wanted to sing it in a live as well.
So, I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Mmm.
The song after that was "Shall We Dance?" by LEO-NI-A.
It's a song that you guys actually love you asked me to sing it after 9:9 because it's also from the uh same series, anime series Shadow House.
But um since, you0, the title itself is "Shall We Dance" and it's a very danceable song, I thought I might as well save it for the live, which I I hope you guys enjoyed.
But um since, you know, the title itself is "Shall We Dance" and it's a very danceable song, I thought I might as well save it for the live, which I I hope you guys enjoyed.
Um I think the choreography was a little difficult for me to learn, but
I I think I pulled it off? Did I did I do okay?
Yes, and the song after that is "Violent," my first original song.
It's very nostalgic to me, um every time I listen to it.
And I guess it's been quite a while since I first released it.
Um, as it was my first original song, I I learned a lot from it and so it it's really special to me.
But as I've said before, um it's been a while since the first original.
So maybe it's time for a second one, sometime soon? Soon? Soon?
[Laughter] But anyways, thank you everyone for always uh supporting me, thanks everyone who helped in making this live happen.
Without you guys, um staff-san, everyone who wanted this wouldn't have happened.
So thank you very, very much. Uh, yeah, I guess we'll move on to the next song.
Uh, I hope you'll enjoy it.
sapphire petals fall through infinite black sea
misty whispers that call, drown in endless dreams
is my sanity clinging from my mem ' ry ?
Is my sanity clinging from my memory?
is humanity a long forgotten friend ?
Is humanity a long-forgotten friend?
天上のだるまが最後の花びらを落とす
Tenjou no yosei ga saigo no hanabira o otosu
心はあなたの嘘をすべて暴く
Kokoro wa anata no uso o subete abaku
enough !!
Enough!
no , i won't keep praying endlessly
No, I won't keep praying endlessly
a world without love is not the world that i want to see
if sentiment withers aoi keshi
tell me how do i reconcile the joy in my memory ?
Tell me how do I reconcile the joy in my memory?
いのちがけど絶まいだい love is now and for forever
Inochikake do zetsumai dai love is now and for forever
古代人はルルイエの家で夢をみながら待つ
Kodaijin wa ruruie no ie de yume o minagara matsu
when death , rebirth , time and oceans align
When death, rebirth, time and oceans align
eternity 's hope will power through
Eternity's hope will power through
天上のだるまが最後の花びらを落とす
Tenjou no yosei ga saigo no hanabira o otosu
心はあなたの嘘をすべて暴く
Kokoro wa anata no uso o subete abaku
enough !!
Enough!
no , i won't keep praying endlessly
No, I won't keep praying endlessly
a world without love is not the...
A world without love is not...
I have to keep reminding myself
I'm not like anyone else
That's my face on my ID
That makes me V.I.P.
No one exactly like this
No one with my fingerprints
No one can touch you like me
今が実るろうそく 最高の日々よ
Now the ripening candle, my greatest days...
They told me, girl, to get your way
You've got to be a bitch in the eyes of all...
今が実るろうそく 最高の日々よ
Now the ripening candle, my greatest days...
A world where love is not the world that I want to see
If such a man glitters, how we can see...
Tell me how, do I reach and save the joy in my memory
今が実るろうそく 最高の日々よ
Now the ripening candle, my greatest days...
命誓い 愛の誓いも
Swearing on life, and swearing on love...
Till death may die, love is now and forever...
あー、いつものように過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
Ah, day after day, the passing time just makes me yawn
ざんざめく夜越え、今日も
Crossing the noisy night, today as well
渋谷の街に朝が降る
Morning falls upon the streets of Shibuya
どこか虚しいようなそんな気持ち
With some kind of empty feeling inside
つまらないな、でもそれでいい
How boring, but that's fine
そんなもんさ、これでいいや
That's just how it is, this is alright
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let your true voice, hidden without knowing, resound, hey
見ないふりしていても確実にそこにある
Even if you pretend not to see, it's definitely there
感じたままに描く 自分で選んだその色で
Draw it just as you felt, in the colors you chose for yourself
眠い空気纏う朝に訪れた青い世界
In the morning wrapped in sleepy air, a blue world arrived
好きなものを好きだと言う怖くて仕方ないけれど
Saying what you love is what you love, even though it's terrifying
本当の自分に出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I finally met my true self
あー、手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに遠くへ行く
Ah, the more I reach out my hands, the further away it goes
思うようにいかない、今日もまた
Not going as I hoped, today as well
焦ったりもがいてる
I'm rushing and struggling
悔しい気持ちもただ情けなくて
Frustrated feelings are just so pathetic
涙がでる、踏み込むほど
Tears well up, the more I step in
苦しくなる、痛くもなる
The more painful and agonizing it becomes
感じたままに進む 自分で選んだこの道を
Moving forward just as I felt, on this path I chose myself
重いまぶた擦る夜にしがみついた青い誓い
Clinging to a blue vow on a night rubbing heavy eyelids
好きなことを続けることそれは「楽しい」だけじゃない
Continuing what you love isn't just "fun"
本当にできる?不安になるけど
Can I really do it? Though I get anxious
何枚でも、ほら何枚でも
Any number of times, hey, any number of times
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ、何回でも、ほら何回でも
Since I lacked confidence, I've kept drawing, any number of times
積み上げてきたことが武器になる
What I've piled up becomes my weapon
周りを見たって、誰と比べたって、僕にしかできないことはなんだ
Looking around, comparing with others, what is the thing only I can do?
今だって自信なんかない、感じたことない気持ち
Even now I have no confidence, feelings I've never felt
知らずにいた想い、あの日踏み出して
Feelings I didn't know, stepping out that day
初めて感じたこの痛みも全部、好きなものと向き合うことで
Facing what I love with all this pain I felt for the first time
ズレた、また小さな光、大丈夫、行こう
Misaligned, yet a small light again, it's alright, let's go
あとは楽しむだけだ、すべてをかけて描く、自分にしか描けない色で
All that's left is to enjoy, drawing with everything, in colors only I can draw
朝の夜も走り続け、見出しだした青い光
Continuing to run through morning and night, finding the blue light
好きなものと向き合うこと、今だって...
Facing what you love, even now...
ああ いつものように 過ぎる日々に あくびが出る
Ah, just like every day,
I yawn as days go by.
さんざめく夜越え 今日も渋谷の街に朝が降る
Through the bustling night,
morning breaks over Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような
Feeling somewhat empty,
そんな気持ち
with that kind of feeling—
つまらないな
how boring.
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly hiding it away,
本当の声を響かせてよ
let your true voice ring out.
さあ 見ないふりしていても
Come on, even if you pretend not to see,
確かにあるよ 今もそこにあるよ
it's definitely there,
still right there.
知らず知らず隠してた
Unknowingly hiding it away,
本当の声を響かせてよ
let your true voice ring out.
さあ 見ないふりしていても
Come on, even if you pretend not to see,
確かにあるよ 君の中に
it's definitely there, inside of you.
あ、Tako、come here. Sit, sit.
Ah, Tako, come here. Sit, sit.
How was the live? Did you enjoy it? How was it? Fun?
How was the live? Did you enjoy it?
How was it? Fun?
I'm glad, I'm glad. Thanks always for your support. Without you this wouldn't have happened.
I'm glad. Thanks always for your support.
Without you, this wouldn't have happened.
Well, it's been a long three years, huh?
Let's continue to have more fun from now on too, okay? Yeah?
Let's continue to have more fun from
now on too, okay? Yeah?
Forever, ever, ever, ever, ever.
Thanks for watching!! It took a while before disSSS!! Thank you always for your support & for your patience in waiting for this live!!
Thanks for watching!! It took a while
before disSSS!! Thank you always for your support
& for your patience in waiting for this live!!
I hope you enjoyed it!! Thank you also to all the staff and everyone who helped make this happen! I'll keep doing my best!! WAH!!!
I hope you enjoyed it!! Thank you also to
all the staff and everyone who helped make this happen!
I'll keep doing my best!! WAH!!!